# YONG SHENG TAN

**4** 6016-3181

in @tanys

Financial technology professional with 9+ years of experience across software development, business analysis and production support looking to further career in a technical or product development role. Adept in managing software delivery lifecycles with a keen understanding of enterprise systems and cloud architecture.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Symphony Communications**

Feb 2019 - Present

Manager, Developer Solutions

- Led engineering team that delivers Symphony's suite of developer tools for building bots and integrations
- Responsible for product roadmap, backlog grooming, delivery management and customer engagement
- Bridged customer domains with technical requirements to ensure developer tools were fit-for-purpose
- Delivered greenfield workflow studio product that facilitates non-developers in building workflows
- Liaised with FINOS to maintain standards of open source project delivery and community contributions

## Developer Relations Technical Lead

- Pioneering lead of team tasked to scale engagement and education of Symphony's developer community
- Subject matter expert on best practices for using developer tools to build bots and integrations
- Responsible for regional outreach to customers on workflow development in collaboration with sales
- Built certification program from scratch, comprising course material, demos, videos, exams and badges
- Developed and ran assets including a developer portal, training center, forum and documentation site
- Organised global events like developer meetups, hackathons, webinars and Innovate conferences

GIC Jun 2016 – Feb 2019

Engineering Lead, Enterprise Applications Technology

- Co-led backend and frontend engineering on a CRM system comprising Java microservices employing Azure cloud components hosted in Kubernetes clusters and a responsive React/Redux web app
- Responsible for scoping requirements, delivery, deployments, support and managing team of developers
- Set up DevOps pipelines in Jenkins/Puppet to enable continuous integration/delivery
- Key developer on innovation award-winning platform for sharing investment ideas across asset classes

## Developer, Public Equities Analytics

- Built Tableau dashboards visualising portfolio exposure, performance and facets for public equities teams
- Led development of equities data mart, designing the structure and ETL workflows in Informatica
- Optimised performance of dashboards through tuning of Oracle databases and batch automation

NatWest Markets Sep 2013 – Mar 2016

Support Analyst, Sales and Trading Analytics

- Provided regional production support for the business intelligence suite used by sales and trading desks
- Responsible for coverage mappings that ensure accurate distribution and reporting of sales income flows
- Built data visualisation dashboards that enabled decision analysis for the APAC wind down programme

#### Business Analyst, Market Risk Technology

- Coordinated with risk managers and development teams to translate issues into implementation outcomes
- Minimised impact to risk sensitivity and VaR metrics from upstream changes through tolerance analysis
- Developed an interactive guide that improved global understanding of the diverse market risk management environment, highlighting relationships of sensitivities used to risk manage products

#### Developer, Operations Technology

- Developed VBA-based tools for operations teams to enable reconciliation, clearing, reporting functions
- Migrated legacy TIBCO middleware scheduled tasks onto a SQL Server Integration Services layer
- Pioneered usage of Python to facilitate straight-through reconciliation of counterparty settlement data

## **EDUCATION**

# **Singapore Management University**

Aug 2009 - Jul 2013

BSc (Information Systems Management), summa cum laude

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer, VMware Spring Professional 2021, Oracle Java Professional